Guide to the Elemer Nagy collection ARCH125
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Elemer Nagy collection
1923-2002
undated
1935-1971
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Nagy, Elemer, 1906-1971
ARCH125
42.9 Linear Feet (132 containers)
The collection contains the works and papers of Elemer Nagy throughout his career as an opera director from 1923-1971. The materials include his set and costume designs, production notes, correspondence and various subject files, as well as a collection of large scenery slides he designed and created for his multi-screen projection system.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Biographical Note
Elemer Nagy was born in 1906 in Kezdivasarhely, Hungary. He was a multitalented member of the Hartt faculty. As director, set designer, and costume designer, Nagy was the main creative talent behind Hartt Opera productions from 1942-1971.
Scope and Contents
The majority of the collection consists of materials pertaining to the creation of opera sets and costumes designed by Elemer Nagy throughout his career as an opera director and stage designer. These materials include colorful drawings, sketches, and tracings of set and costume designs, as well as production notes and large lantern slides he created to project scenery.
The collection also includes photographs of his opera productions, as well as of Nagy, his colleagues, and photographs used for his work. The collection also consists of publicity materials, correspondence and other papers, as well as opera programs and in some cases the designs for the program artwork. There are also two costumes designed by Nagy in the collection.
Related Materials
Hartt School Collection
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in nine series: I. Set and Costume Designs, II. Scenery Slides, III. Production Notes, IV. Photographs, V. Subject Files, VI. Publicity and Scrapbooks, VII. Opera Programs, Printed Ephemera, and Their Designs, VIII. Artifacts, and IX. Duplicates.
Opera; Opera -- Stage-setting and scenery; Opera -- Production and direction; Costume design; blueprints (reprographic copies); Correspondence; Photographs; slides (photographs); lantern slides; costumes (character dress); Set designers; Costume designers; design drawings; Hartt Opera-Theater Guild; Hartt College of Music
- Set and Costume Designs, 1935-1971; I
  Scope and Contents
  The Set and Costume Design series consists of drawings of Nagy's costumes and sets. Costumes designs sometimes include fabric swatches.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged into two subseries: a. Final Designs and b. Sketches and Tracings.
  - Final Designs, 1935-1962; undated
    These drawings are the final, colored designs by Elemer Nagy of sets and costumes for operas. Occasionally some designs appear to be incomplete, but are much more refined than the kinds of drawings found in the sketches and tracings sub-series.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by opera title.
    - Albert Herring, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 1)
    - Amahl and the Night Visitors, undated; 4 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 1, Box Set and Costume Design 31)
    - Amelia Goes to the Ball, undated; 3 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 1)
    - Ariadne auf Naxos, undated; 3 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 46)
    - Armide, 1956-1957; undated; 22 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 1, Box Set and Costume Design 2, Box Set and Costume Design 31, Box Set and Costume Design 46)
    - Barber of Seville, 1946-1949; undated; 6 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 3, Box Set and Costume Design 44)
    - Bastien and Bastienne, 1949; undated; 3 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 3, Box Set and Costume Design 31)
    - Beauty and the Beast, 1945; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 46)
    - Beautiful Galatea, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 3)
    - Bluebeard's Castle, 1945; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 3)
    - Cosi Fan Tutti, undated; 2 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 31, Box Set and Costume Design 32)
    - Cupid Goes to Boarding School, 1947; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 3)
    - Deidama, 1951, undated; 10 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 3, Box Set and Costume Design 4)
    - The Devil and Daniel Webster, 1953; 1951; 2 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 4, Box Set and Costume Design 46)
    - Dido and Aeneas, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 4)
    - Don Giovanni, 1955; 5 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 5)
    - Don Pasquale, 1945-1959; 17 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 5, Box Set and Costume Design 32, Box Set and Costume Design 46)
    - Falstaff, 1953, undated; 18 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 6, Box Set and Costume Design 7, Box Set and Costume Design 32)
    - Faust-Gounoud, 1952-1957; 28 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 7, Box Set and Costume Design 8, Box Set and Costume Design 9, Box Set and Costume Design 33)
    - Fidelio, undated; 3 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 46)
    - Die Fledermaus, 1944; 1949; 18 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 9, Box Set and Costume Design 10, Box Set and Costume Design 32)
    - Forza del Destino, undated; 12 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 10, Box Set and Costume Design 33, Box Set and Costume Design 46, Box Set and Costume Design 50)
    - Frantic Physician, 1941; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 11)
    - Frogs, 1947; 4 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 11, Box Set and Costume Design 47)
    - Gianni Schicci, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 47)
    - Goosehead and the Goblin, 1949; 5 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 11)
    - Gypsy Baron, 1957; undated; 30 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 11, Box Set and Costume Design 12, Box Set and Costume Design 13, Box Set and Costume Design 14, Box Set and Costume Design 44)
    - Hansel and Gretel, 1942; 2 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 33, Box Set and Costume Design 44)
    - Headless Horseman, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 14)
    - Headless Horseman?/Princess and the Vagabond?, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 33)
    - HMS Pinafore, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 14)
    - Il Travatore, 1952; 1953; 8 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 14)
    - Johnny Appleseed, 1956; 2 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 15)
    - La Sonnambula, undated; 18 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 15, Box Set and Costume Design 16, Box Set and Costume Design 48)
    - La Voyante, undated; 3 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 44)
    - Leander and Hero, 1955; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 33)
    - Little Red Riding Hood, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 17)
    - L'ivronge corrige, 1945; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 33)
    - Love of Three Oranges, 1954-1955; undated; 8 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 17, Box Set and Costume Design 34)
    - Macbeth, 1952, undated; 2 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 17, Box Set and Costume Design 34)
    - Madame Butterfly, 1950-1953; undated; 24 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 17, Box Set and Costume Design 18, Box Set and Costume Design 34)
    - Magic Flute, undated; 2 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 47)
    - Marriage of Figaro, 1951-1955; 31 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 19, Box Set and Costume Design 20, Box Set and Costume Design 35, Box Set and Costume Design 44, Box Set and Costume Design 48)
    - Martha, 1946-1976; 3 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 21, Box Set and Costume Design 48)
    - Medea, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 21)
    - Mefistofele, undated; 3 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 35, Box Set and Costume Design 48)
    - Merry Wives, undated; 2 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 21)
    - Midsummer Night's Dream, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 36)
    - Miranda and the Dark Young Man, 1952; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 21)
    - Old Man and the Thief, 1943; undated; 3 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 21, Box Set and Costume Design 44)
    - Pearl Fishers, undated; 7 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 21, Box Set and Costume Design 36)
    - Peer Gynt, undated; 9 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 22, Box Set and Costume Design 36, Box Set and Costume Design 48)
    - Philemon and Baccus, 1957; 2 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 22)
    - Princess and the Vagabond, 1948; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 22)
    - Rigoletto, 1957; 7 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 22, Box Set and Costume Design 23)
    - Romeo and Juliet, 1951; 43 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 24, Box Set and Costume Design 25, Box Set and Costume Design 26, Box Set and Costume Design 36, Box Set and Costume Design 37)
    - Servant of Two Masters, 1955; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 37)
    - Susannah, undated; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 27)
    - Tales of Hoffman, undated; 5 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 27, Box Set and Costume Design 48)
    - Ten Girls and No Men, 1942; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 44)
    - Ten Maidens, 1942; 6 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 27)
    - Tosca, 1952-1956; 7 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 27, Box Set and Costume Design 37, Box Set and Costume Design 38)
    - Touchstone, undated; 2 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 27)
    - Trial by Jury, 1952; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 28)
    - Tubby the Tuba, undated; 10 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 28)
    - Whitewings, 1942; 1 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 28)
    - Unidentified, 1935-1962; 85 Pieces (Box Set and Costume Design 29, Box Set and Costume Design 30, Box Set and Costume Design 38, Box Set and Costume Design 39, Box Set and Costume Design 44, Box Set and Costume Design 48, Box Set and Costume Design 49)
  - Sketches and Tracings, 1942-1971; undated
    This sub-series consists of sketches and tracings for costume and set designs. Some of the oversized drawings were created for the large lantern slides which were used for projecting scenery.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by opera title. In instances in which a file inclues multiple operas, it is arranged by the first title in the filename.
    - Abduction from the Seralio, 1968; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 49)
    - Amahl and the Night Visitors, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Armide/Abduction/Macbeth Witches, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Barber of Seville, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Bastien and Bastienne, 1944; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Beauty and the Beast, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Chanticleer, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Devil and Daniel Webster/Headless Horseman, 1944; 1953; undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Deidama, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Dido and Aeneas?/Armide?, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Don Giovanni, 1955; 2 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Don Pasquale, Undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Falstaff, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 49)
    - Faust/Mephistopheles, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 40)
    - Die Fledermaus, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Forza del Destino/Traviata, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Frogs of Aristophanes, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Goosehead and the Goblin, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Gypsy Baron, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Hamlet, 1946; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Hansel and Gretel, 1942; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Headless Horseman, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Hin and Zurick, 1942; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - La Sonnambula, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Love for Three Oranges, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Madame Butterfly, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Marriage aux Laternes, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Marriage of the Devil, 1944-1945; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 41)
    - Marriage of Figaro/Cosi/Magic Flute/Man on the Moon, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 42)
    - Merry Wives of Windsor, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 42)
    - Pearl Fishers, 1971; undated; 2 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 42)
    - Romeo and Juliet, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 42)
    - Peer Gynt, undated; 4 Folders; 2 Folders Projected scenery slide tracings 30 x 40 inch flat file folder (Box Set and Costume Design 42, Box Set and Costume Design 51, Box Set and Costume Design 52)
      Includes two flat file drawer folders of tracings used for Nagy's projected scenery slides.
    - Polifem, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 43)
    - Philemon and Baucis, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 43)
    - Rigoletto, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 43)
    - Stage Perspective, 1950-1952; 3 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 43)
    - Ten Girls and No Men, 1942; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Tosca, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 43)
    - Touchstone, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 43)
    - La Traviata, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 43)
    - Tuba [?] Symphony, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 43)
    - Unidentified, undated; 5 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 43)
    - Unidentified Hindemeth and Suppe Operas, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - The Young God, undated; 1 Folders (Box Set and Costume Design 45)
- Scenery Slides, undated; II (Box Scenery Slides 1, Box Scenery Slides 2, Box Scenery Slides 3, Box Scenery Slides 4, Box Scenery Slides 5, Box Scenery Slides 6, Box Scenery Slides 7, Box Scenery Slides 8, Box Scenery Slides 9, Box Scenery Slides 10, Box Scenery Slides 11, Box Scenery Slides 12, Box Scenery Slides 13, Box Scenery Slides 14, Box Scenery Slides 15, Box Scenery Slides 16, Box Scenery Slides 17, Box Scenery Slides 18, Box Scenery Slides 19, Box Scenery Slides 20, Box Scenery Slides 21, Box Scenery Slides 22, Box Scenery Slides 23, Box Scenery Slides 24, Box Scenery Slides 25, Box Scenery Slides 26)
  This series contains large lantern slides that were created by Elemer Nagy to project scenery for his opera productions. Nagy made these slides primarily with cutouts of various colored transparencies, with additional details drawn on, sandwiched between two pieces of acrylic sheeting.
- Production Notes, 1942-1971; undated; III
  This series contains notes and documents pertaining to the production of the opera, including set and lighting plans, handwritten notes, casting information, and occasionally music and scripts.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by opera title.
  - Abduction from the Seraglio, 1947; 1968-1969 (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 1)
  - Adriane auf Naxos, 1959; 1965 (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 2, Box Production Notes 9)
  - Aida, 1965 (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 3)
  - Albert Herring, undated (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 4)
  - Amahl and The Night Visitors, undated (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 5)
  - Andrean Chenir, 1970 (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 6)
  - Armide, 1957 (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 7)
  - Barber of Seville - NYC Opera, 1966 (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 8)
  - Beauty and the Beast, undated (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 9)
  - Boris Godonov, undated (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 10)
  - Carmelites, undated (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 11)
  - Central City, 1952-1956 (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 12)
  - Children's Operas, undated (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 13)
  - Cosi Fan Tutti, 1959-1961 (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Crucible, undated (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 16)
  - Deidama, undated (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 17)
  - Don Pasquale, 1965 (Box Production Notes 1, Folder 18)
  - Don Quixote, 1965 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 1)
  - Duena, 1970 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 2)
  - Gypsy Baron Central City, 1957 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 3)
  - Fact or Fiction, undated (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 4)
  - Falstaff, 1961 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 5)
  - Faust - Mobile Alabama, 1970 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 6, Box Production Notes 6, Folder 1)
  - Faust, 1971 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 7, Box Production Notes 10)
  - Fidelio, undated (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 8)
  - Fledermaus - Baltimore Civic Opera, 1956 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 9)
  - Frantic Physician, 1960-1961 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 10)
  - Gianni Schicci, undated (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 11)
  - Hansel and Gretel, undated (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 12)
  - Headless Horseman, 1962-1963 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 13)
  - Here and There, 1942 Nov 9 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 14)
  - La Boheme, 1967 (Box Production Notes 2, Folder 15, Box Production Notes 3, Folder 1, Box Production Notes 6, Folder 2)
  - La Boheme - Fort Worth with Placido Domingo, 1971 (Box Production Notes 3, Folder 2, Box Production Notes 6, Folder 3)
  - La Forza del Destino Toronto, 1959 (Box Production Notes 3, Folder 3-4, Box Production Notes 7)
  - Love of Three Oranges, 1949 (Box Production Notes 3, Folder 5)
  - Lovely Galatea, undated (Box Production Notes 3, Folder 6)
  - Macbeth, 1953 (Box Production Notes 3, Folder 7)
  - Madame Butterfly - Central City, 1950 (Box Production Notes 3, Folder 8)
  - Magic Flute, 1967 (Box Production Notes 3, Folder 9, Box Production Notes 4, Folder 1)
  - Marriage of Figaro, 1952-1955 (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 2)
  - Martha, 1954 (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 3)
  - Masked Ball, undated (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 4)
  - Medea, 1970 Jan (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 5)
  - Mephistofele - Aspen, 1969 (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 6)
  - Mefistophele, undated (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 7)
  - Merry Wives, undated (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 8)
  - Miranda, 1956 (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 9)
  - Old Maid and the Thief, 1943 (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 10)
  - Pearl Fishers, undated (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 11)
  - Peer Gynt, 1965-1966 (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Das Pensionat, undated (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 14)
  - Philemon and Baucis, 1957 (Box Production Notes 4, Folder 15)
  - Prelude and Fugue, undated (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 1)
  - Princess and Vagabond, undated (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 2)
  - Rigoletto, 1956 (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 3, Box Production Notes 8)
  - Romeo and Juliet, 1960 (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 4, Box Production Notes 6, Folder 5)
  - Salome, undated (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 5)
  - Sister Angelica, 1970-1971 (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 6)
  - Tales of Hoffman, 1968 (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 7, Box Production Notes 6, Folder 6)
  - Touchstone, undated (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 8)
  - Traviata, 1960 (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 9, Box Production Notes 6, Folder 7, Box Production Notes 11)
  - Turandot, 1967 (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 10, Box Production Notes 6, Folder 8)
  - La Vida Breve, 1969 (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 11, Box Production Notes 6, Folder 4)
  - White Wings, 1949 (Box Production Notes 5, Folder 12-14)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box Production Notes 6, Folder 9)
- Photographs, 1937-1971; undated; IV
  This series contains photographs of Elemer Nagy's productions, as well as photographs of Nagy, his colleagues, his designs, and images he used as inspiration for his work.
  The series is arranged into four sub-series: a. Subject File, Scrapbook, and Publicity Photograph Prints, b. Production Photograph Prints, c. Slides, and d. Transparencies and Negatives.
  - Subject File, Scrapbook, and Publicity Photograph Prints, Circa 1939-1970; undated
    This sub-series consists of print photographs that were removed from files within the Subject File series and the Scrapbook and Publicity series.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Aspen Music Festival, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 1)
    - Birthday, 1969 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 2)
    - Central City, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 3)
    - Central City Scrapbook, Circa 1946 - circa 1950 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 4)
    - Dance Class, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 5)
    - Fledermaus (Central City), 1949 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 6)
    - Hartt Opera Portfolio, undated (Circa 1960?) (Box Photographs 1, Folder 7)
    - Multiscreen Scenery Projection System, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 8)
    - Opera for Children, 1969-1970 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 9)
    - Photographs of Elemer "Doc" Nagy, 1966, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 10-11, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Scrapbook of Theatre Model Reconstructions by Elemer Nagy, Circa 1939 - circa 1942 (Box Photographs 6)
    - Sets - Not at Hartt, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 12)
    - Singers and Friends, 1941-1949, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 13)
    - Tanglewood, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 14)
    - TV Station WRGB, 1942-1943 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 15)
    - White Wings, 1949 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 16)
  - Production Photograph Prints, 1937-1971; undated
    This subseries consists of photographs of Nagy's opera productions, as well as photographs of his designs, and photographs that appear to have been used for inspiration during the design process.
    - Abduction From The Seraglio, 1971 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 17)
    - Albert Herring, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 18-19)
    - Andrean Chenier - Mobile Alabama, 1970 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 20)
    - Amahl and the Night Visitors, 1952; undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 21, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Apothecary, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 22)
    - Ariadne auf Naxos, 1959; 1965; undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 23-24)
    - Armide, 1957 Feb 9 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 25)
    - Barber of Seville, 1947 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 26)
    - Barber of Seville - NYC Opera, 1966 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 27)
    - Bastien and Bastienne, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 28)
    - Beautiful Alaten, 1952 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 29)
    - Beauty and the Beast, undated (Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Benjamin Britten's Opera, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 30)
    - Boris Godunov, undated (Box Photographs 1, Folder 31)
    - La Boheme, 1966 (Box Photographs 1, Folder 32)
    - Central City, 1952-1956 (Box Photographs 2, Folder 1-7)
    - Comedy on the Bridge, undated (Box Photographs 2, Folder 8)
    - Cosi Fan Tutti, 1961; undated (Box Photographs 2, Folder 9-10, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - The Crucible, 1969; undated (Box Photographs 2, Folder 11-12, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Cupid Goes to Board School (Yale?), undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 1)
    - Deidama, 1956; undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 2, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Devil and Daniel Webster, Storbridge with Paranov, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 3)
    - Dialogues of the Carmelites, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 4)
    - Dido and Aneas - St. Joseph, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 5)
    - Dido and Aneas - Yale, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 6)
    - Die Rauber, 1937 (Box Photographs 3, Folder 7)
    - Don Giovanni, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 8)
    - Don Pasquale, 1951; 1965 (Box Photographs 3, Folder 9-10)
    - Don Quixote, 1965 (Box Photographs 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Duenna Prokofiev, 1970; undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 13-14)
    - Falstaff, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 15)
    - Faust - Fort Worth, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 16)